For Use in Publications
Marist Archives and Special Collections
For Use in Publications
2.1.3.4
Marist College
  Box 1532
- For Use in Publications, 2.1.3.4
  - For use in publications: Lowell Thomas (alone), circa 1915 - early 1930s; 1 (Box 1532)
    - Lowell Thomas- the world traveler and explorer - photographed on one of his expeditions into the Arctic. His most recent journey was to the Tropics and he has just returned from a [?], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas- the world traveler and explorer - photographed on one of his expeditions into the Arctic. His most recent journey was to the Tropics and he has just returned from a [?], 1-verso
    - L.T. in the Arctic before he was 21, 2
    - Verso: L.T. in the Arctic before he was 21, 2-verso
    - Please return to Frances Ryan, 1315 Milwaukee St., Denver, 3
    - Verso: Please return to Frances Ryan, 1315 Milwaukee St., Denver, 3-verso
    - A new photograph of Lowell Thomas, author of "Count Luckner, the Sea Devil ," whose new book of the exploits of the U-Boats during the war, "Raiders of the Deep ," has just been published by Doubleday Doran Verso: 1928, 4
    - Note: A new photograph of Lowell Thomas, author of "Count Luckner, the Sea Devil ," whose new book of the exploits of the U-Boats during the war, "Raiders of the Deep ," has just been published by Doubleday Doran Verso: 1928, 5
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 6
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 7
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 8
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas] [4 copies], 9
    - Verso: Kindly credit photo: Lewis F. Nathan, 9-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 10
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 11
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 12
    - Verso: Camera portrait by Hal Phyfe, 50 W 56, 1508 Circle, 12-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 13
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 14
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas; Kindly credit Phyfe, 867 Madison Ave., New York, 14-verso
  - For use in publications: Lowell Thomas (alone), 1930s; 2 (Box 1532)
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas reading a book], 1
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas next to a large globe], 2
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas at a typewriter] [3 copies], 3
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas] [7 copies], 4
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 5
    - [Fox(?), 1938], 6
    - Verso: Fox(?), 1938, 6-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas on the telephone], 7
  - For use in publications: Lowell Thomas (alone), circa 1930s - 1950s; 3 (Box 1532)
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas in front of a snow-covered tree], 1
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 2
    - L.T. going places on Blue Sunoco!, 3
    - Verso: L.T. going places on Blue Sunoco!, 3-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas with the head of a hippo mounted on the wall], 4
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas dressed for cold weather], 5
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas standing on a boat floating on icey waters (?)], 6
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 7
    - Looking over a New Jersey development, hunting for ideas. C.E. Engelbrecht, Lake Mohawk, Sparta, N.J., 8
    - Verso: Looking over a New Jersey development, hunting for ideas. C.E. Engelbrecht, Lake Mohawk, Sparta, N.J., 8-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 9
    - Note: Subject: Lowell Thomas On Air: Mon. Thru Fri., 6:45-7:00 PM, EDT 8/1/50, 10
    - Lowell Thomas, 11
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas, 11-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas next to a CBS microphone] [2 copies], 12
    - Copyright 1952, Samuel Goldwyn Productions, Inc., 13
    - Verso: Copyright 1952, Samuel Goldwyn Productions, Inc., 13-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas sitting on a "radiation" barricade], 14
    - May 1955; Original Photograph by Hal Phyfe, 15
    - Verso: May 1955; Original Photograph by Hal Phyfe, 15-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 16
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 17
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas during a broadcast (?)] [4 copies], 18
  - For use in publications: Lowell Thomas (alone), circa 1950s - 1970s; 4 (Box 1532)
    - Hi Hansom- Remember I had a 1.00 dollar camera and wanted to prove that we didn't need a 1000.00 [?] to take good pictures Regards and best to Fran, [Ben?], 1
    - Verso: Hi Hansom- Remember I had a 1.00 dollar camera and wanted to prove that we didn't need a 1000.00 [?] to take good pictures Regards and best to Fran, [Ben?], 1-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas] [2 copies], 2
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 3
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas] [11 copies], 4
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 5
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas holding a microphone] [2 copies], 6
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 7
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas], 8
    - Done for Minneapolis, 1966, 9
    - Verso: Done for Minneapolis, 1966, 9-verso
    - Air France - Relations Exteriures, 2 Rue Marbeuf - Paris; Reproduction Autorisee Sans Droits contre envoi de 2 justificatifs; Mention Obligatoire: Collection Air-France, 10
    - Verso: Air France - Relations Exteriures, 2 Rue Marbeuf - Paris; Reproduction Autorisee Sans Droits contre envoi de 2 justificatifs; Mention Obligatoire: Collection Air-France, 10-verso
    - Irving Kaufman Studios, 222 E. 44th ST., N.Y. 17, N.Y., Murray Hill 7-8343, 11
    - Verso: Irving Kaufman Studios, 222 E. 44th ST., N.Y. 17, N.Y., Murray Hill 7-8343, 11-verso
    - Verso: Dec 19, 1961, 12
    - Verso: Dec 19, 1961, 12-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas standing in front of the Sphynx in Egypt (?)], 13
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas with head of a tiger], 14
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas in front of a microphone], 15
    - LT as MC at Apr '72 Explorers Annual Banquet holding N.G. gourd, 16
    - Verso: LT as MC at Apr '72 Explorers Annual Banquet holding N.G. gourd, 16-verso
    - Said to be where it happened, in Woodington. Pic taken at nite. Oct. 19 1977; Compliments of Greenville Daily Advocate, 17
    - Verso: Said to be where it happened, in Woodington. Pic taken at nite. Oct. 19 1977; Compliments of Greenville Daily Advocate, 17-verso
    - John Dornes, The Edwardian Photographer, Box 398 Monroe, N.Y., 18
    - Verso: John Dornes, The Edwardian Photographer, Box 398 Monroe, N.Y., 18-verso
    - [Photograph of Lowell Thomas posing with a bust], 19
    - Robert G. Elliott, 1227 Oakwood Ave., Daytona Beach, Fla. 32014; 4-22-76, 20
    - Verso: Robert G. Elliott, 1227 Oakwood Ave., Daytona Beach, Fla. 32014; 4-22-76, 20-verso
    - Please credit Bill Mark, Park Sheraton Hotel [3 copies], 21
    - Verso: Please credit Bill Mark, Park Sheraton Hotel, 21-verso
  - For use in publications: Lowell Thomas with President Franklin Delano Roosevelt, circa 1930s; 5 (Box 1532)
    - Lowell Thomas and President Franklin D. Roosevelt at one of the annual games between the White House Correspondents and Lowell Thomas's Nine Old Men team, 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and President Franklin D. Roosevelt at one of the annual games between the White House Correspondents and Lowell Thomas's Nine Old Men team, 1-verso
    - Beginning of novalty; L.T. and President Franklin Delano Roosevelt [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: Beginning of novalty; L.T. and President Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 2-verso
    - Note: Lowell Thomas and President Franklin D. Roosevelt shared the same stomping ground, the Mid-Hudson Valley. Mr. Thomas lived in Pawling, New York, and President Roosevelt, in Hyde Park, New York, some 20 miles away. Verso: Beginning of rivalry; Gonzalez Studio, 515 Madison Ave., 3
    - Lowell Thomas and President Franklin D. Roosevelt [close-up, 5 copies], 4
    - President Franklin D. Roosevelt in car and sitting ballplayers, 5
  - For use in publications: Frances Ryan Thomas with Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1940s; 6 (Box 1532)
    - [Man (?) getting into the cockpit of a plane] [4 copies], 1
    - [Man and woman with dog], 2
  - For use in publications: Afghanistan, 1921 - 1922; 7 (Box 1532)
    - Note: L.T. welcomed by Afridi chiefs in the mountains of Waziristan, the No Man's Land of Central Asia Verso: Afghanistan-No. 61. Persian Minister and Mr. Lowell Thomas, on a balcony at the palace of the Persian legation in Kabul, 1
    - Afghanistan-No.61. Persian Minister and Mr. Lowell Thomas, on a balcony at the palace of the Persian legation in Kabul., 2
    - Verso: Afghanistan-No.61. Persian Minister and Mr. Lowell Thomas, on a balcony at the palace of the Persian legation in Kabul., 2-verso
    - [same photo as 7.2 with L.T. cutout], 3
  - For use in publications: Artwork, undated; 8 (Box 1532)
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 1
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 2
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 3
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 4
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 5
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 6
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 7
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 8
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 9
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 10
    - Richard S. Debo 200 Moross Road Grosse Point Farms Michigan 48236, 11
    - Note: Richard S. Debo 200 Moross Road Grosse Point Farms Michigan 48236, 12
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas], 13
    - [Drawing of Lowell Thomas], 14
    - [Painting of Lowell Thomas] [17 copies], 15
  - For use in publications: Potential posters, circa 1930s; 9 (Box 1532)
    - Lowell Thomas (Advertising Club News), 6/1/37, 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas (Advertising Club News), 6/1/37, 1-verso
    - [mounted portrait of Lowell Thomas], 2
    - [red plastic L.T. silhouette], 3
    - [red plastic L.T. silhouette], 4
  - For use in publications: Tibet, 1949; 10 (Box 1532)
    - Note: The Potala Palace, or "The Palace of the Gods," rises 900 feet above the Lhasa Plain. From street level, this is approximately two-thirds the height of the Empire State Building. The photograph was taken by Lowell Thomas, Jr. on his journey to Tibet with his father in 1949., 1
    - [Photograph of The Potala Palace], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas riding a donkey along a stone pathway], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving a gift from a man (?)], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas eating with other people], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas posing with three women and a man], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas holding a child, posing with several other people], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting at a table looking at a box], 8
  - For use in publications: World War I, 1917 - 1918; 11 (Box 1532)
    - L.T. operating an anti-aircraft gun on the Italian front, 1
    - Note: L.T. operating an anti-aircraft gun on the Italian front, 2
    - L.T. shaking hands with Major Baracca, Italy's Number One flying ace in the World War, 3
    - Note: L.T. shaking hands with Major Baracca, Italy's Number One flying ace in the World War, 4
    - L.T. interviewing a Jewish colonist in the Holy Land during the war, 5
    - Note: L.T. interviewing a Jewish colonist in the Holy Land during the war, 6
    - A curious contrivance called a steel otter. L.T. and an officer in the royal Naval Reserve are having a look at this monster which was used in the Mediterranean by the British to sweep up mines. This picture was taken on board a British munitions ship that was making its way through the mine fields and submarine-infested waters of the Mediterranean. Verso: An otter on board British merchant vessel in Mediterranean. These otters were to sweep up mines, 7
    - Note: A curious contrivance called a steel otter. L.T. and an officer in the royal Naval Reserve are having a look at this monster which was used in the Mediterranean by the British to sweep up mines. This picture was taken on board a British munitions ship that was making its way through the mine fields and submarine-infested waters of the Mediterranean. Verso: An otter on board British merchant vessel in Mediterranean. These otters were to sweep up mines, 8
    - L.T. wearing army campaign hat, accompanied by two members of his staff, rowing down one of the canals of Venice, during the war when Venice was almost a deserted city. The Austrians and Germans were pounding away with their artillery just fourteen miles across the lagoons [Major Piero Tozzi on left, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. on right], 9
    - Note: L.T. wearing army campaign hat, accompanied by two members of his staff, rowing down one of the canals of Venice, during the war when Venice was almost a deserted city. The Austrians and Germans were pounding away with their artillery just fourteen miles across the lagoons [Major Piero Tozzi on left, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. on right], 10
    - L.T. and two of his colleagues, on a journey along the canals of Venice at a time when the City of Canals was almost deserted. The Austrians were banging away with their artillery just fourteen miles distant and nearly the entire population had fled [Major Piero Tozzi on left, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. on right] [2 copies], 11
    - Note: L.T. and two of his colleagues, on a journey along the canals of Venice at a time when the City of Canals was almost deserted. The Austrians were banging away with their artillery just fourteen miles distant and nearly the entire population had fled [Major Piero Tozzi on left, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. on right], 12
    - Mr. and Mrs. L.T. and Major Piero Tozzi, at the Leaning Tower of Pisa., 13
    - Note: Mr. and Mrs. L.T. and Major Piero Tozzi, at the Leaning Tower of Pisa., 14
    - L.T. on the first passenger aeroplane flight from Egypt to Palestine, 15
    - Verso: L.T. on the first passenger aeroplane flight from Egypt to Palestine, 15-verso
    - L.T. as an aviator movie man ready to start over the lines in the World War., 16
    - Verso: L.T. as an aviator movie man ready to start over the lines in the World War., 16-verso
    - L.T. and T. E. Lawrence in Arab garments, 17
    - Verso: L.T. and T. E. Lawrence in Arab garments, 17-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas on right, in trench with soldiers], 18
    - [autographed by Lowell Thomas: "With best wishes for a long life crammed with high adventure. Lowell Thomas", 19
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting on a sled pulled by dogs], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas with a guide pointing out to the mountains], 21
  - For use in publications: Miscellaneous photographs, circa 1920s - 1960s; 12 (Box 1532)
    - IN 25th RADIO YEAR Lowell Thomas, CBS Radio newscaster who has become a "friend of the family" to millions of American listeners, has just entered his 25th broadcasting year. Here the adventurous newsman, who has reported from far-flung exploring posts around the globe, does some research in his vast library for his current activities with the Monday-thru-Friday evening "Lowell Thomas and the News" and with his Cinerama project [circa 1954], 1
    - Note: IN 25th RADIO YEAR Lowell Thomas, CBS Radio newscaster who has become a "friend of the family" to millions of American listeners, has just entered his 25th broadcasting year. Here the adventurous newsman, who has reported from far-flung exploring posts around the globe, does some research in his vast library for his current activities with the Monday-thru-Friday evening "Lowell Thomas and the News" and with his Cinerama project [circa 1954], 2
    - [circa 1954], 3
    - [from left to right: Lowell Thomas, Jr., Frances Ryan Thomas, Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, Lowell Thomas], 4
    - L.T. with son, Lowell, Jr. Pawling, NY, 5
    - Verso: L.T. with son, Lowell, Jr. Pawling, NY, 5-verso
    - Cap Cities file- Murphy, Frank Smith, LT went on Big Board, 6
    - Note: Cap Cities file- Murphy, Frank Smith, LT went on Big Board, 7
    - Major "Hap" Arnold when he was L.T.'s pilot, in 1922. Later he became a 5 star general with 2.5 million men in his command, 8
    - Verso: Major "Hap" Arnold when he was L.T.'s pilot, in 1922. Later he became a 5 star general with 2.5 million men in his command, 8-verso
    - [from right to left: Sam Pryor, Will Hays, Frances Ryan Thomas, President Herbert Hoover, Mrs. Will Hays], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas riding an elephant], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas with two other men], 12
    - [Photograph of a notebook], 13